A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1954
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.632
This collection consists of 10,200 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred to the library. Date unknown.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Contents List
- General Files, 1954
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 1)
  - Academic Organization (folder empty) 1954 (Box 1)
  - Admissions (college) 1954 (Box 1)
  - Air Force 1954 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association 1954 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund, University of Virginia 1954 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors (folder empty) 1954 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1954 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1954 (Box 1)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" (folder empty) 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" (folder empty) 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "X - Y - Z" 1954 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1954 (Box 2)
  - Army - General 1954 (Box 2)
  - Army - ROTC Transportation 1954 (Box 2)
  - Army - Judge Advocate General's Office 1954 (Box 2)
  - Art 1954 (Box 2)
  - Art Commission 1954 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Colleges 1954 (Box 2)
  - Association of American Universities 1954 (Box 3)
  - Association of Governing Boards of State Universities 1954 (Box 3)
  - Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1954 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1954 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 1954 (Box 3)
  - Athletics: January - June 1954 (Box 3)
  - Athletics: July - December 1954 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - Commonwealth Day 1954 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1954 (Box 3)
  - Athletics - Attorney General 1954 (Box 3)
  - "Ba -Bl" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 4)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 4)
  - Biology 1954 (Box 4)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1954 (Box 4)
  - Blandy Farm 1954 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1954 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Cemetery (folder empty) 1954 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Chemistry (folder empty) 1954 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Electricity 1954 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Roads 1954 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - General 1954 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Architects and Engineers 1954 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Academic Building 1954 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Children's Rehabilitation Center 1954 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Contracts 1954 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - J.A.G. Dormitory 1954 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Life Science Building (folder empty) 1954 (Box 4)
  - Building Program - Medical Buildings 1954 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Men's Dormitories 1954 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Naval Armory (folder empty) 1954 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Physics Building 1954 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Power Plant and Heating Mains 1954 (Box 5)
  - Building Program - Student Activities Building 1954 (Box 5)
  - Bursar: January - June 1954 (Box 5)
  - Bursar: July - December 1954 (Box 5)
  - Business Administration, School of 1954 (Box 5)
  - Byrd, Harry F. 1954 (Box 5)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 6)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 6)
  - Cavalier Daily 1954 (Box 6)
  - Chemistry 1954 (Box 6)
  - Chemistry - John Lee Pratt Trace Analysis Laboratory: 6th Annual Report 1954 (Box 6)
  - Civilian Defense 1954 (Box 6)
  - Classics 1954 (Box 6)
  - Clippings 1954 (Box 6)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1954 (Box 6)
  - Committee - Academic Legislation 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Administrative Policy of Hospital 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Admissions (College) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Admissions - Special 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - American Committee for ɭigr頓cholars 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Art Museum 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Athletic 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Balch Bequest 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm (Replacement of Professor White Committee) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Board 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Calendar 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Catalogue 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Cemetery 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Chapel 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - College Reorganization (Appointment of Dean, etc.) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Fraternity 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations (folder empty) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Conference Housing Situation (folder empty) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Danforth Foundation 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Education, special program of training teachers 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Extension 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Extension, to Review work of 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Extension, 2-year college program 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Extension, Work in Wise County 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Fellowship Awards (folder empty) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Final Comprehensive Examinations in the College 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Fire Protection 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Foreign Affairs 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Graduate School of Business (folder empty) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Honors Courses 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Hospital Architectural Advisory 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Housing for Conferences (see Conference Housing Committee) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Institute of Public Affairs (folder empty) 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences Council 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Judge Advocate General Dormitory 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Lectures - Special 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Lectures - Page-Barbour and J. W. Richard Lectures 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Library 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Lower Division 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - McConnell Award 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Mary Washington College 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Medical Board of the Hospital 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Mountain Lake Biological Station 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Nursing School Advisory 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Patents 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Pre-Medical Evaluation 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Processions 1954 (Box 7)
  - Committee - Public Occasions 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Research 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Rhodes Scholarship 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Richmond Area University Center Council 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Rules and Courses - College 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Rules and Courses - Graduate 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Rules and Courses - Medical 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Rushton Seminars (folder empty) 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Schedule and Classroom Assignments 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Scholarships, Loans and Employment 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Science 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Student Affairs 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Student Faculty Relations 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Student Union 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Summer Session 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Summer Session Degrees - College 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Summer Session Degrees - Graduate 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Teacher Placement 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Tree 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Virginia Advisory on Schools and Colleges 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Virginia Quarterly Review1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of University Students 1954 (Box 8)
  - Committee - White, Professor O. E. - Replacement (see Blandy Farm) (folder empty) 1954 (Box 8)
  - Comptroller (State) 1954 (Box 8)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1954 (Box 8)
  - Council of State Governments 1954 (Box 8)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 8)
  - Davis, W. H. 1954 (Box 8)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 9)
  - Economics: January - June 1954 (Box 9)
  - Economics: July - December 1954 (Box 9)
  - Education 1954 (Box 9)
  - Endowment 1954 (Box 9)
  - Endowment - Contingent Fund 1954 (Box 9)
  - Engineering 1954 (Box 9)
  - English 1954 (Box 10)
  - Enrollment 1954 (Box 10)
  - Extension Division: January - June 1954 (Box 10)
  - Extension Division: July - December 1954 (Box 10)
  - Faculty 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Bayly-Tiffany 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Ford 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Thomas Jefferson 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Ryan 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - William A. Smith Memorial 1954 (Box 11)
  - Finals 1954 (Box 11)
  - Food Service 1954 (Box 11)
  - Foreign Affairs 1954 (Box 11)
  - Forestry 1954 (Box 11)
  - Founder's Day 1954 (Box 11)
  - Fraternities 1954 (Box 11)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 12)
  - Garden Club 1954 (Box 12)
  - General Education Board 1954 (Box 12)
  - Geography 1954 (Box 12)
  - Geology 1954 (Box 12)
  - Gifts and Grants 1954 (Box 12)
  - Governor's Office 1954 (Box 12)
  - Governor's Office - Approval of Gifts and Grants 1954 (Box 12)
  - Graduate 1954 (Box 12)
  - "Ha - Hk" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 13)
  - "Hl - Hz" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 13)
  - Highway Department 1954 (Box 13)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1954 (Box 13)
  - History 1954 (Box 13)
  - Honor System 1954 (Box 13)
  - Hospital: January - June 1954 (Box 13)
  - Hospital: July - December 1954 (Box 13)
  - Hospital - Blue Cross 1954 (Box 13)
  - Hospital - Medical Board 1954 (Box 13)
  - Hospital - Monthly Statistical Reports 1954 (Box 13)
  - Housing 1954 (Box 13)
  - Hull Foundation 1954 (Box 13)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 14)
  - Institute of International Education 1954 (Box 14)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1954 (Box 14)
  - Insurance 1954 (Box 14)
  - International Association of Universities 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "A" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "B" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "C" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "D" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "E" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "F" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "G" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "H" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "I" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "J" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "K" 1954 (Box 14)
  - Invitations - "L" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "M" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "N" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "O" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "P" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "Q" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "R" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "S" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "T" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "U" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "V" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "W" 1954 (Box 15)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1954 (Box 15)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 16)
  - Japan Christian University 1954 (Box 16)
  - Jefferson - Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 16)
  - Jefferson Birthplace Memorial Park Commission (folder empty) 1954 (Box 16)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation 1954 (Box 16)
  - Jefferson Bicentennial (folder empty) 1954 (Box 16)
  - Jefferson Portrait 1954 (Box 16)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 16)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 16)
  - Law School 1954 (Box 16)
  - Lectures - General 1954 (Box 16)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour 1954 (Box 17)
  - Lectures - Richard 1954 (Box 17)
  - Legal Matters 1954 (Box 17)
  - Legislative Program 1954 (Box 17)
  - Library 1954 (Box 17)
  - Library - Board of Alderman (folder empty) 1954 (Box 17)
  - Library - McGregor 1954 (Box 17)
  - Lower Division 1954 (Box 17)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 17)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 17)
  - "Mi - Mz" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 17)
  - Madison Hall 1954 (Box 17)
  - Mary Washington College - Dockets 1954 (Box 18)
  - Mary Washington College - Report to the Chancellor of Mary Washington College on its Conversion into a College of Liberal Arts 1954 (Box 18)
  - Mathematics 1954 (Box 18)
  - Medicine 1954 (Box 18)
  - Military - Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 18)
  - Music 1954 (Box 18)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 18)
  - National Association of State Universities 1954 (Box 18)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1954 (Box 18)
  - National Education Association 1954 (Box 18)
  - National Science Foundation 1954 (Box 18)
  - Navy - General 1954 (Box 18)
  - Navy - ROTC 1954 (Box 18)
  - Nursing School 1954 (Box 18)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 20)
  - Oak Ridge 1954 (Box 20)
  - "Pa - Pe" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 20)
  - "Pf - Pz" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 20)
  - Personnel (State) 1954 (Box 20)
  - Personnel and Placement 1954 (Box 20)
  - Phi Beta Kappa 1954 (Box 20)
  - Philosophy 1954 (Box 20)
  - Photographs 1954 (Box 20)
  - Physical Education 1954 (Box 20)
  - Physics 1954 (Box 20)
  - Political Science 1954 (Box 20)
  - President's Council 1954 (Box 20)
  - Psychology 1954 (Box 20)
  - Purchase and Printing (State) 1954 (Box 20)
  - Purchase Office (University) 1954 (Box 20)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 20)
  - Questionnaires 1954 (Box 20)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 21)
  - Radio 1954 (Box 21)
  - Raven Society 1954 (Box 21)
  - Recommendations 1954 (Box 21)
  - Regional Education 1954 (Box 21)
  - Registrar 1954 (Box 21)
  - Religion 1954 (Box 21)
  - Requisitions 1954 (Box 21)
  - Research - General 1954 (Box 22)
  - Research - Army (folder empty) 1954 (Box 22)
  - Research - Bureau Population and Economic 1954 (Box 22)
  - Research - Bureau of Public Administration 1954 (Box 22)
  - Research - Institute for Research in Social Sciences 1954 (Box 22)
  - Research - Medical (folder empty) 1954 (Box 22)
  - Research - National Research Council 1954 (Box 22)
  - Richmond University Center 1954 (Box 22)
  - Rockefeller Foundation 1954 (Box 22)
  - Romance Languages 1954 (Box 22)
  - Rural Social Economics 1954 (Box 22)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 22)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 22)
  - Salaries 1954 (Box 23)
  - Segregation 1954 (Box 23)
  - Selective Service 1954 (Box 23)
  - Senate 1954 (Box 23)
  - Sigma Xi 1954 (Box 23)
  - Sociology 1954 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1954 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1954 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry 1954 (Box 23)
  - Southern Association of Land-Grant Colleges and State Universities 1954 (Box 23)
  - Southern University Conference 1954 (Box 23)
  - Speech and Drama 1954 (Box 23)
  - Speeches and Articles 1954 (Box 23)
  - State Board of Education 1954 (Box 23)
  - State Universities Association 1954 (Box 23)
  - Statistics 1954 (Box 23)
  - Student Aid Office 1954 (Box 23)
  - Student Affairs - General 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "A" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "B" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "C" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "D" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "E" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "F" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "G" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "H" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "I" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "J" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "K" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "L" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "M" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "N" 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "O" (folder empty) 1954 (Box 24)
  - Student Affairs - "P" 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs - "Q" (folder empty) 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs - "R" 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs - "S" 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs - "T" 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs - "U" (folder empty) 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs - "V" 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs - "W" 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Affairs - "X - Y - Z" 1954 (Box 25)
  - Student Health Department 1954 (Box 25)
  - Sullivan Award (folder empty) 1954 (Box 25)
  - Summer Session 1954 (Box 25)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 25)
  - Taft Memorial 1954 (Box 25)
  - Television 1954 (Box 25)
  - Travel 1954 (Box 25)
  - Treasurer of Virginia 1954 (Box 25)
  - Treasury Department 1954 (Box 25)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 26)
  - U. S. Office of Education 1954 (Box 26)
  - University News Service 1954 (Box 26)
  - University Press 1954 (Box 26)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 26)
  - Veterans 1954 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1954 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1954 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Education Association 1954 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Institute for Scientific Research 1954 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1954 (Box 26)
  - Virginia Chamber of Commerce 1954 (Box 26)
  - Visitors: January - June 1954 (Box 26)
  - Visitors: July - December 1954 (Box 26)
  - Visitors - Dockets and Minutes 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Black 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Judge Barksdale 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Carrington 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Coxe 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Ms. Dunn 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Dr. Emmett 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gay 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gravatt 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gray 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Howard 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. McWane 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Mears 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Herbert M. Smith 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Howard Smith 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mr. Talbott 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Wailes 1954 (Box 27)
  - Visitors - Ms. Wheeler 1954 (Box 27)
  - "Wa - Wh" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 28)
  - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 28)
  - Wilson, Woodrow - Birthplace Foundation 1954 (Box 28)
  - Women, Dean of 1954 (Box 28)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1954 (Box 28)
  - 633
  - "A-Am" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 1)
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 1)
  - Academic Organization (folder empty) 1955 (Box 1)
  - Admissions 1955 (Box 1)
  - Air Force 1955 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Fund 1955 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Association 1955 (Box 2)
  - American Association of University Professors (folder empty) 1955 (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education 1955 (Box 2)
  - American Education Week 1955 (Box 2)
  - Annual Reports 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"A" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"B" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"C" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"D" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"E" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"F" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"G" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"H" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"I" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"J" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"K" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"L" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"M" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"N" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"O" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"P" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"Q" (folder empty) 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"R" 1955 (Box 2)
  - (Box 2)
  - Applications--"S" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"T" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"U" (folder empty) 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"V" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"W" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Applications--"X-Y-Z" 1955 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1955 (Box 2)
  - Army--General 1955 (Box 3)
  - Army--Judge Advocate General's (J.A.G.) School 1955 (Box 3)
  - Army--ROTC 1955 (Box 3)
  - Art (folder empty) 1955 (Box 3)
  - Art Commission 1955 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges 1955 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities 1955 (Box 3)
  - Association of Governing Boards of state Universities (folder empty) 1955 (Box 3)
  - Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1955 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1955 (Box 3)
  - Athletics (2 folders) 1955 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--Commonwealth Day 1955 (Box 4)
  - Athletics--NCAA 1955 (Box 4)
  - Astronomy 1955 (Box 4)
  - Attorney General 1955 (Box 4)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1955 (Box 4)
  - "Ba-Bl" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 4)
  - "Bm-Bz" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 5)
  - Bibliographical Society 1955 (Box 5)
  - Biology 1955 (Box 5)
  - Biology--Mountain Lake (folder empty) 1955 (Box 5)
  - Blandy Farm 1955 (Box 5)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1955 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--General 1955 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Architects and Engineers 1955 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Children's Rehabilitation Center 1955 (Box 5)
  - Building Program--Contracts (folder empty) 1955 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--J.A.G. Dormitory 1955 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Life Science Building (folder empty) 1955 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Medical Building 1955 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Physics Building 1955 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Piedmont 1955 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Power Plant and hearing Mains 1955 (Box 6)
  - Building Program--Student Activities Building 1955 (Box 6)
  - Bursar (2 folders) 1955 (Box 6)
  - Business Administration, Graduate School of 1955 (Box 7)
  - Byrd, Senator Harry F. 1955 (Box 7)
  - "Ca-Ck" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 7)
  - "Cl-Cz" Miscellaneous 1955 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie Foundation 1955 (Box 7)
  - Cavalier Daily 1955 (Box 7)
  - Chemistry 1955 (Box 8)
  - Chemistry--John Lee Pratt Trace Analysis Laboratory 1955 (Box 8)
  - Civilian Defense 1955 (Box 8)
  - Classics 1955 (Box 8)
  - Clippings 1955 (Box 8)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1955 (Box 8)
  - Commerce, McIntire Undergraduate School 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committees 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Academic Legislation (folder empty) 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Accounts 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Advanced Standing for Exceptional Students 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Administration Policy of Hospital (folder empty) 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award (folder empty) 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Art Museum (folder empty) 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Athletic 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Atlantic Union 1955 (Box 8)
  - Committee--Balch Estate 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Blandy Farm 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Board 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Calendar (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Catalogue 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Cemetery 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Chapel 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Chaperones 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--College Reorganizations 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Contractual Relations 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Debts (see Accounts Committee) (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Education, Dean of 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Education Program of Special Training for Handicapped Children 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--English Department--Special Committee 1955 (Box 9)
  - Committee--Extension (folder empty) 1955 (Box 9)